James H. Madison papers, 1901-2011 C514
Indiana University Archives
James H. Madison papers
1901-2011
1982-1998
Indiana University Archives
Madison, James H.
C514
18.4 Cubic feet 19 boxes
James Madison is the Thomas and Kathryn Miller Professor Emeritus of History at Indiana University. He graduated from Indiana University and has spent nearly his entire career teaching at IU. The collection largely consists of materials relating to his written works and extensive service activities both at IU and within the state. Of particular interest are the notes and drafts for his books Eli Lilly: A Life, 1885-1977 (1989), Indiana Through Tradition and Change (1982), and The Indiana Way: A State History (1986). The collection also contains correspondence, class syllabi, various committee materials, and materials related to his activities within the History Department.
Access Restrictions
Select files closed to researchers. Restricted materials are listed where they would fall in the intellectual arrangement of the collection but are physically located in the last boxes of the collection.
Advance notice required for access to collection.
Biographical Note
James H. Madison was born on October 5, 1944, in York County, Pennsylvania. He attended Gettysburg College where he received his Bachelor of Arts in 1966. Madison received his Master of Arts in 1968 and his Ph.D. in 1972 from Indiana University. From 1972 to 1973, he was a Harvard-Newcomen Postdoctoral Fellow in Business History at Harvard University.
In 1973, Madison returned to Indiana University as a Visiting Assistant Professor of History and Visiting Associate Editor of the Journal of American History. In 1976, Madison was named Assistant Professor of History and Editor of the Indiana Magazine of History. In 1981, he became an Associate Professor. Madison served as an Exchange Professor at the University of Kent during the 1982-1983 academic year. He served as chair of the History Department from 1993-1997. Madison was a Fulbright Professor at Hiroshima University in Japan during the 1997-1998 academic year. In 2000, Madison became Thomas Milton Miller and Kathryn Owens Miller Professor of History. He served as Director of the Liberal Arts and Management Program from 2003-2009. Madison retired from IU in 2011 and was given the title Thomas and Kathryn Miller Professor of History Emeritus. Over the course of his tenure at IU, Madison was the recipient of several awards including the Sylvia E. Bowman Distinguished Teaching Award and the IU Student Alumni Association "Student Choice" Award.
Madison has authored multiple books including Indiana Through Tradition and Change (1982), The Indiana Way: A State History (1986), Eli Lilly: A Life, 1885-1977 (1989), Wendell Willkie: Hoosier Internationalist (1992), A Lynching in the Heartland: Race and Memory in America (2001), Slinging Doughnuts for the Boys: An American Woman in World War II (2007), World War II: A History in Documents (2010), Hoosiers: A New History of Indiana (2014), and The Ku Klux Klan in the Heartland (2020). He has served on the Board of Indiana Humanities, as a trustee of the Indiana Historical Society, and as a member of the Indiana Bicentennial Commission.
Madison married Jeanne Myers on August 26, 1967. Jeanne is a biologist who worked in the IU Department of Biology and later managed IU's Lifelong Learning and Mini University programs.
Madison's notable books related to Indiana history include, Indiana Through Tradition and Change (1982), The Indiana Way: A State History (1986), Eli Lilly: A Life, 1885-1977 (1989), and Wendell Willkie: Hoosier Internationalist (1992). He has served as associate editor of the Journal of American History and as editor of the Indiana Magazine of History.
Arrangement
The collection is organized into four series: Writings, Indiana University service, Activities outside Indiana University, and Correspondence. Writings is further organized into two subseries: Books and Articles and book reviews. Indiana University service is further broken down into General, Class syllabi, and IU committees.
Scope and Content Note
The materials found in the James H. Madison papers consist of written publications, research material, records related to both his professorial duties as a professor at Indiana University and his professional activities outside of IU, and correspondence. The collections covers Madison's early career up through the mid-2000s.
The Writings and research Series (1901-2010) consists of Madison's books, articles and book reviews, and the research notes and drafts related to Madison's published works. The series is divided into two subseries: Books and Articles and book reviews. Book materials are grouped chronologically by the date of publication of the book, and within the subseries materials related to each book are organized alphabetically. The articles and book reviews are arranged chronologically.
The Indiana University series (1968-2011) consists of materials related to Madison's roles and duties in his various professorial positions during his time at IU, beginning as an Assistant Professor and culminating as Professor Emeritus. The General subseries contains general information about the history department, Madison's professional tasks, and a small amount concerning his doctoral degree. The Teaching materials subseries consists of a large selection of class syllabi as well as a few exams. The IU Committees subseries contains materials related to a variety of academic committees, such as the Budget Policy Committee, the COAS (College of Arts and Sciences) Task Force on Teaching, and the Liberal Arts and Management Program (LAMP).
The Outside professional service series (1974-2005) consists of materials related to Madison's professional activities outside of Indiana University. These activities include participation in local and state committees and events. These include the Organization of American Historians, the Midwestern Regional History and Culture Series, Connor Prairie, and Indiana Historical Society activities.
The Correspondence series (1973-2001) contains written correspondence between Madison, colleagues, historians, and publishers.
Photographs Pulled
143 photographs, 8 slides, and 1 photograph booklet were removed from Box 3. 3 photographs were removed from Box 5. 1 video cassette removed from Box 9. The photos were added the Archives Photograph Collection.
Related Material
Additional publications and research materials may be accessed IUScholarworks
Related photographs may be available in the University Archives Photographs Database
Acquisition Information
2011/047; 2012/141
Provenance
Transferred from James Madison to the University Archives, June 2011 and August 2012.
Historians --Indiana --Bloomington --History --Sources.; History --Study and teaching (higher) --Indiana --Bloomington --History --Sources.; Indiana University, Bloomington. Department of History -- Faculty -- Archives; Madison, James H. -- Archives; Madison, James H. -- Correspondence
- Writings and research, 1901-2010; undated (Box 1)
  - Books, 1901-2010; undated
    - Indiana Through Tradition and Change: A History of the Hoosier State and its Peoples 1920-1945 (Box 1)
      - Paperback, 1982 (Box 1)
      - Bibliographical Essay, 1980 (Box 1)
      - Chapter I: The State and the People, 1980 (Box 1)
      - Chapter II, 1980 (Box 1)
      - Chapter II: The Politics of the 1920s, undated (Box 1)
      - Chapter IV: The Politics of the 1930s, 1979 (Box 1)
      - Chapter VI: Business, Labor, and the Economy, 1980 (Box 1)
      - Chapter VII: Transport, 1920-1940; 1980 (Box 1)
      - Chapter IX: Education and Religion, 1977-1978 (Box 1)
      - Chapter X: Public Health, 1980 (Box 1)
      - Chapter XI: Leisure, Sports, and Culture, 1980 (Box 1)
      - Chapter XII: World War II at Home, 1980 (Box 1)
    - The Indiana Way: A State History (Box 1)
      - Hardback, 1986 (Box 1)
      - Chapter I (Box 1)
        - Outlines, 1982 (Box 1)
        - People and Empire Before the Americans, undated (Box 1)
      - Chapter II, 1982 (Box 1)
      - Chapter 1-7, undated (Box 1)
      - A History of Indiana Part III, undated (Box 1)
      - Illustrations, 1985 (Box 1)
      - Maps, Charts, Appendix, Preface, and Index, 1986 (Box 1)
      - Miscellaneous, 1984 (Box 1)
      - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 1)
      - Notes, 1986 (Box 1)
      - Part III (Box 1)
        - Indiana in Transition, 1850-1920; undated (Box 1)
        - Chapter I, 1982-1983 (Box 1)
        - Chapter II: Making a Living: The Indiana Economy, 1850-1920; 1982 (Box 1)
        - Chapter 3: Hoosier Together, 1983 (Box 1)
        - Chapter 4: Indiana Politics, 1873-1920; 1983 (Box 1)
        - Superseded Drafts and Notes, 1984 (Box 1)
      - Permissions, 1985 (Box 1)
      - Superseded Drafts and Notes, 1984 (Box 1)
    - Comparative Histories of the Heartland (Box 2)
      - 1985-1988 (Box 2)
      - Unsolicited Comments, 1987-1988 (Box 2)
      - Authors, 1987 (Box 2)
      - Introduction The States of the Midwest: An Introduction Drafts, 1987 (Box 2)
      - Maps, 1987 (Box 2)
      - Post-Publication, 1987-1990 (Box 2)
    - Eli Lilly: A Life, 1885-1977 (Box 2)
      - Hardback, 1989 (Box 2)
      - Archeology, 1969-1996 (Box 2)
      - Evelyn Fortune Lilly Bartlett, 1986 (Box 2)
      - Biography, 1984-1985 (Box 2)
      - Landrum R. Bolling, 1988 (Box 2)
      - Chapter 8, Philanthropy, undated (Box 2)
      - Christ Church (for Lilly book), 1958-1988 (Box 2)
      - Allen Clowes, 1988 (Box 2)
      - James B. Cope, 1987 (Box 2)
      - Mildred Compton, 1988 (Box 2)
      - James B. Cornelius, 1988 (Box 2)
      - Deposition, William Fortune Trust, 2000 (Box 2)
      - The Drug Industry, 1989 (Box 2)
      - Early Years, undated (Box 2)
      - Eli Lilly Information, 1901-1932 (Box 2)
      - Madeline Fortune Elder, 1985 (Box 2)
      - James E. Farmer, 1987-1988 (Box 2)
      - William Fortune, 1983-1990 (Box 2)
      - James B. Griffin, 1986 (Box 2)
      - Roger S. Gray, 1987-1988 (Box 2)
      - Hubert H. Hawkins, 1987 (Box 2)
      - History of Pharmacy (for Lilly book), 1988 (Box 2)
      - Byron P. Hollett, 1985-1999 (Box 2)
      - John C. Householder, 1986 (Box 2)
      - Sam Jones, 1988 (Box 2)
      - James H. Keller, 1986 (Box 2)
      - The Later Years, undated (Box 2)
      - Peter R. Lawson, 1986-1987 (Box 2)
      - Lilly - Angel Mounds and Glenn Black Lab, 1987-1988 (Box 2)
      - Lilly Archive, undated (Box 2)
      - Lilly Biography Outline, 1986 (Box 2)
      - Lilly Center, 1981-1986 (Box 2)
      - Lilly Draft Chapters 1-4, 1987 (Box 2)
      - Lilly Notes, 1985 (Box 2)
      - Lilly, President, 1932 (Box 2)
      - J.K. Lilly III, 1986 (Box 2)
      - Esther Linenberger, 1987 (Box 2)
      - John S. Lynn, 1988 (Box 2)
      - Anita Martin, 1988 (Box 2)
      - Francis Martin, 1986 (Box 2)
      - Gene E. McCormick, 1988 (Box 3)
      - H. Roll McLaughlin, 1960-1987 (Box 3)
      - Virginia Minton, undated (Box 3)
      - Paul Moore, Jr., 1986-1987 (Box 3)
      - C. Ellie Nelson, 1988 (Box 3)
      - Waldemar A. Nielsen, 1988 (Box 3)
      - Manning Patillo, 1988 (Box 3)
      - John H. Peatling and Lucile Barber, 1988 (Box 3)
      - Howard Peckham, 1985-1986 (Box 3)
      - Pharmacy, 1988-1989 (Box 3)
      - Pharmacy in History Article, 1988 (Box 3)
      - Philanthropy, undated (Box 3)
      - Photographs for Eli Lilly book not used or duplicate, undated (Box 3)
        Separated Materials
        (68 photographs and 8 slides removed)
      - John G. Rauch Jr., 1988 (Box 3)
      - Research Notecards for Lilly book, undated (Box 3)
        General
        (See Box 18)
      - Reminiscences of Eli Lilly, 1966-1969 (Box 3)
      - Reprints for Eli Lilly book, undated (Box 3)
        (75 photographs and 1 booklet removed)
      - Research Expenses, Lilly Biography, 1985-1989 (Box 3)
      - Robert H. Rhodehamel, 1986 (Box 3)
      - Richard O. Ristine, 1988 (Box 3)
      - Swan, John Patrick Dissertation (Box 3)
        - Chapter 3, 1985 (Box 3)
        - Chapter 6, 1985 (Box 3)
        - Chapter 7, 1985 (Box 3)
      - Gayle Thornbrough, 1988 (Box 3)
      - Erminie Wheeler-Voegelin, 1986 (Box 3)
      - Earl D. Wallace, 1988-1889 (Box 3)
      - Frederick and Margaret Weber, 1988 (Box 3)
      - Charles Webb, 1988 (Box 3)
      - Carl J. Weinhardt, Jr., 1986 (Box 3)
      - J. Reid Williamson, Jr., 1989 (Box 3)
      - Richard D. Wood, 1988 (Box 3)
    - Wilkie drafts and correspondence for book Traces article, and American National Biography, 1989-1997 (Box 3)
    - A Lynching in the Heartland: Race and Memory in America (Box 3)
      - Paperback, 2001 (Box 3)
      - Chapters 1, 1B, 3-6, 1997-1999 (Box 3)
      - Chapters 7-8, 1999 (Box 3)
    - Bloomington Past and Present Hardback, 2002 (Box 3)
    - Slinging Doughnuts for the Boys: An Amercian Woman in World War II Hardback, 2007 (Box 3)
    - World War II: A History in Documents Paperback, 2010 (Box 3)
  - Articles and Book Reviews, 1969-2010; undated
    - Oppositions to the Mexican War in Indiana, 1846-1848, 1969 (Box 3)
    - The Evolution of Commercial Credit Reporting Agencies in Nineteenth-Century America Research, 1973 (Box 3)
    - The Evolution of Commercial Credit Reporting Agencies in Nineteenth-Century America Business History Review, Summer, 1974 (Box 3)
    - Arthur D. Whiteside, in Dictionary of American Biography,", 1975 (Box 3)
    - Business and Politics in Indianapolis: The Branch Bank and the Junto 1837-1846, 1975 (Box 3)
    - The Credit Reports of R.G. Dun & Co. As Historical Sources, 1975 (Box 3)
    - Some Thoughts and Questions for a Study of The Rise of Big Business and the City Research, 1975 (Box 3)
    - Communications, Dictionary of American Economic History, 1976-1979 (Box 4)
    - Charles Warren Fairbanks: Politician, in Gentlemen from Indiana, 1977 (Box 4)
    - Indiana Newspaper Clippings and Pamphlets, 1980-1989 (Box 4)
    - 'No Cheap Pudding,' State History Journals and American History Institute News, 1982 (Box 4)
    - John D. Rockefeller's General Education Board and the Rural School Problem in the Midwest 1900-1930 in History of Education Quarterly, 1984 (Box 4)
    - Celebrating Indiana 1816, 1916, 2016, 1984-2000 (Box 4)
    - Federalism Clippings, 1987 (Box 4)
    - John D. Rockefeller's General Education Board and the Rural School Problem in the Midwest 1900-1930 in History of Education Quarterly (Box 4)
      - 1984 (Box 4)
      - Notes, 1982 (Box 4)
        (Oversized, See Box 17)
    - Outside Agents of Change and Midwestern Community Institutions 1850-1950, 1984 (Box 4)
    - The American Constitution and the Old Federalism: Views from the Hoosier State, 1985 (Box 4)
    - Bonnet House (home of Evelyn Fortune Bartlett article in Connoisseur, January 1985 (Box 4)
    - Reformers and the Rural Church, 1900-1950 (Box 4)
      - 1985-1988 (Box 4)
      - Reprint from Journal of American History, 1986 (Box 4)
    - Hoosiers at War 1941-1945 in Traces, 1991 (Box 4)
    - Midwest at Noon: An Introduction, 1990-1991 (Box 4)
    - Pledged to One World, with Liberty and Justice for All Indiana Alumni Magazine, 1991 (Box 4)
    - Introduction to John Martin book Indiana: An Introduction, 1992-1993 (Box 4)
    - Diverging Trails: Why the Midwest is not the West Frontier and Region, 1993 (Box 4)
    - Why History Shouldn't be Swept Under the Carpet Indiana Alumni Magazine, 1995 (Box 4)
    - The Indiana University Department of History, 1895-1995: a Centennial Year Sketch (Box 4)
    - Introduction for Recollections of a Combat Medic in WW2 by Bernard Rice, 1996-1997 (Box 4)
    - The Midwest in Encyclopedia of The United States in the Twentieth Century, 1996 (Box 4)
    - "A Top Ten Teaching Topic: The American Home Front During WWII " Queen City Heritage, 1996 (Box 4)
    - Is There a Black Heartland? Black Heartland, 1997 (Box 4)
    - Essays - miscellaneous, 1998-2002 (Box 4)
    - Images of the KKK Traces, 1999 (Box 4)
    - Flossie Bailey: 'What a Woman!' in Traces, 1999 (Box 4)
    - Traces article, Commemorating the Past: The Indiana Territory, 1800-2000, 2000-2001 (Box 4)
    - Traces article, An Indiana Lynching and Stories of Race, 2000-2001 (Box 4)
    - The State of Indiana History 2000 (Box 4)
    - A Lynching Story, 2001 (Box 4)
    - Lilly, Eli (1885-1977) entry in Philanthropy in America, 2004 (Box 4)
    - Banking, 1830s and 1840s, Used in Chapter 2, undated (Box 4)
    - Klu Klux Klan Research, undated (Box 4)
    - Notes, General, undated (Box 4)
    - Book Reviews (Box 4)
      - 1970-1979 (Box 4)
      - 1980-1989 (Box 4)
      - 1990-1999 (Box 4)
      - 2000-2010 (Box 4)
- Indiana University, 1968-2011; undated
  - General, 1968-2011; undated
    - Advisor, 1989-1993 (Box 4)
    - Associate Instructor Board/Review, 1998-2000 (Box 4)
    - Dan Bailey, 1987-1989 (Box 5)
    - CA Workshop, September 2005 (Box 5)
    - C.V, undated (Box 5)
    - Canterbury (Box 5)
      - 1987-2011 (Box 5)
      - 2000-2001 (Box 5)
    - Chemistry Budget Conference, 1993 (Box 5)
    - Faculty Summary Reports, 1975-2004 (Box 5)
    - James P. Fadely, 1989-1992 (Box 5)
    - Financial - Education, 1968-1982 (Box 5)
    - Finances - trip to Huntington Library, 1988-1989 (Box 5)
    - Fischelis Scholar Award, 1987-1988 (Box 5)
    - Fulbright + Europe, 1981-1982 (Box 5)
    - Fulbright Scholarship, Hiroshima University, 1997-1998 (Box 5)
    - Grant Proposals, 1984-1994 (Box 5)
    - History Department to June 1993, 1991-1993 (Box 5)
    - Humanities Achievement Award, 1992 (Box 5)
    - IU - Indianapolis, 1987-1988 (Box 5)
    - Manuscript Collections, 1987 (Box 5)
    - Newberry Fellowship, 1977-1978 (Box 5)
    - Ph.D. Exams, 1977-2000 (Box 5)
    - Placement (Box 5)
      - 1973-1974 (Box 5)
      - 1974-1975 (Box 5)
    - Planner, 1997 (Box 5)
    - Promotion, 1988-1989 (Box 5)
    - Promotion to Full Professor, Originals of Unsolicited Letters, 1981-1988 (Box 5)
    - Promotion to Full Professor, Research, 1983-1987 (Box 5)
    - Research Topics and Grants, 1987-1997 (Box 5)
    - Sabbatical/Leave, 1981-1991 (Box 5)
    - Salary, 1985-2010 (Box 6)
    - Selective Service, 1966-1968 (Box 6)
    - Sylvia Bowman Award, 1994 (Box 6)
    - V - Supporting Documents, Research Related, 1975-1980 (Box 6)
    - V- Supporting Documents, Service Related, 1977-1980 (Box 6)
    - V- Supporting Documents, Research, Publications, 1975-1980 (Box 6)
    - University of Kent, 1982-1983 (Box 6)
    - Kyle Williams, 1990-1991 (Box 6)
    - Phyllis Zimmerman, 1987 (Box 6)
  - Teaching Materials, 1973-2002; undated
    - A303 [The United States, 1789-1829] (Box 6)
      - 1975-1978 (Box 6)
      - Fall, 1975 (Box 6)
      - Fall, 1978 (Box 6)
    - A304[The United States, 1829-1865], 1976 (Box 6)
    - A333 [History of Indiana I], Spring, 1981 (Box 6)
    - A334 [History of Indiana 1850 to the Present] (Box 6)
      - Spring, 1977 (Box 6)
      - Spring, 1978 (Box 6)
      - Spring, 1979 (Box 6)
      - 1979-1981 (Box 6)
      - Spring, 1980 (Box 6)
    - A363 [Survey of Indiana History] (Box 6)
      - Summer, 1982 (Box 6)
      - Fall, 1983 (Box 6)
      - Summer, 1985 (Box 6)
      - Summer, 1986 (Box 6)
      - Spring, 1987 (Box 6)
      - Spring, 1989 (Box 6)
      - Summer, 1990 (Box 6)
      - Spring, 1991 (Box 6)
      - Summer, 1991 (Box 6)
      - Spring, 1993 (Box 6)
      - Spring, 1994 (Box 6)
      - Fall, 1995 (Box 6)
      - Spring, 1997 (Box 6)
      - Spring, 1999 (Box 6)
      - Summer, 1999 (Box 6)
      - Fall, 1999 (Box 6)
      - Exams, 1983-2002 (Box 6)
    - Fall 1997 Classes, Notes, Etc. (Box 6)
    - Freshman Seminar, 1993 (Box 6)
    - Intensive Freshman Seminars, 1997 (Box 6)
    - H105 [American History General Course I] (Box 6)
      - Fall, 1973 (Box 6)
      - Lectures, 1973-1989 (Box 6)
      - Fall, 1974 (Box 6)
      - Spring, 1975 (Box 6)
      - Fall, 1976 (Box 6)
      - Fall, 1979 (Box 6)
      - Fall, 1980 (Box 6)
      - Spring, 1984 (Box 6)
      - Spring, 1985 (Box 6)
      - Exams, 1985-1988 (Box 7)
    - H106 [U.S. History, 1865-1975] Old Lectures (Box 7)
      - 1974-1977 (Box 7)
      - Video Cassette, Lecture, J. Madison, August, 1994 (Box 7)
        (Separated from collection)
      - Fall, 1977 (Box 7)
      - Spring, 1990 (Box 7)
      - Fall, 1990 (Box 7)
      - Spring, 1992 (Box 7)
      - Summer, 1992 (Box 7)
      - Exams, 1992-2002 (Box 7)
      - Fall, 1993 (Box 7)
      - Skills Course, 1994 (Box 7)
      - Fall, 1994 (Box 7)
      - Spring, 1996 (Box 7)
      - Fall, 1998 (Box 7)
      - Lectures, 1998-2000 (Box 7)
      - 2000 (Box 7)
      - Fall, 2002 (Box 7)
      - Discussion Section, undated (Box 7)
      - Films, undated (Box 7)
    - H422-H425 [Social and Political Conflict in Indiana, 1816-1980], Fall, 1981 (Box 7)
    - H593 [Teaching United States History], 2000 (Box 7)
    - H650 [Colloquium United States History], Fall, 1988 (Box 7)
    - H650 [Introduction to Graduate Study in American History], Fall, 1989 (Box 7)
    - H650, 1996 (Box 7)
    - H750 [Seminar in US History], Spring, 1987 (Box 7)
    - Intensive Freshman Seminars, 1997 (Box 7)
    - J200 [The United States Home Front during World War II] (Box 8)
      - Spring, 1995 (Box 8)
      - Fall, 1999 (Box 8)
      - Spring, 2001 (Box 8)
    - J400 [US Home Front During World War II] (Box 8)
      - Fall, 1988 (Box 8)
      - Fall, 1996 (Box 8)
    - J475 [Seminar for History Majors: The United States Home Front During World War II] (Box 8)
      - Fall, 1991 (Box 8)
      - Fall, 1992 (Box 8)
    - Preparing Future Faculty Program, 1997-2000 (Box 8)
    - Reading Courses, 1980-2001 (Box 8)
    - S860 [Communities, States, & Regions in American History], 1982 (Box 8)
    - Spring Classes, Hiroshima University, 1998 (Box 8)
    - W300 [World War II: The Peoples] (Box 8)
      - Spring, 2001 (Box 8)
      - Fall, 2001 (Box 8)
    - Overhead Maps, undated (Box 8)
    - Overhead Transparencies to accompany The Unfinished Nation, undated (Box 8)
  - Committees, 1975-2009
    - 21st Century Teachers Project, 2001-2002; (unlabeled floppy) (Box 8)
    - African-American History Search Committee, 2003 (Box 8)
      Conditions Governing Access
      Restricted
    - African-American Studies Chair Search, 2001-2002 (Box 8)
    - Art Museum Policy Committee, 1991-1993 (Box 8)
    - Associate Vice Chancellor for Multicultural Affairs Search, 1999 (Box 8)
    - Blake Tenure Committee, 1992-1993 (Box 8)
    - Budget Policy Committee, 1992 (Box 8)
    - Budget Conferences, 1993 (Box 8)
    - Chancellor Search, 2000-2001 (Box 8)
    - COAS [College of Arts and Sciences] Task Force on Teaching (Box 8)
      - 1991-1992 (Box 8)
      - 1993 (Box 8)
    - Department of History Executive Committee, 1977-1978 (Box 8)
    - Department of History Field Committees, 2002-2003 (Box 8)
    - Development of the Donald F. Carmony Chair in Indiana History, 1997 (Box 8)
    - Donald F. Carmony Chair in Indiana History Search, 2001 (Box 8)
    - Dissertation Committees, 1978-2005 (Box 8)
    - Ellen Dwyer Promotoion, 2004 (Box 8)
    - Faculty Research Account, 1989-1992 (Box 8)
    - Fellowship AI [Associate Instructor], 2001 (Box 8)
    - Fellowship and AI [Associate Instructor] Committee (Box 8)
      - 1983-1984 (Box 8)
      - 1985 (Box 8)
      - Spring, 1986 (Box 8)
      - 1991-1992 (Box 8)
      - 1992/1993 (Box 8)
    - Financial Aid, Fellowship Applications, 1981-1984 (Box 8)
    - History of Philanthropy Search, 1992 (Box 9)
    - History Department Executive Committee (Box 9)
      - 1993 (Box 9)
      - 1998-1999 (Box 9)
    - Historic Preservation Committee, 1998 (Box 9)
    - Honors Division Review, 1992 (Box 9)
    - The Indiana University Department of History, 1895-1995: A Centennial Sketch (Box 9)
    - IU Museum Committee, 1977-1984 (Box 9)
    - Indiana University Museum Review Committee, 1981 (Box 9)